elon musk says don't defy defy
the bank of america says that defy could
be potentially more disruptive than
bitcoin and mark cuban says that defy
is the future in a world where
governments are printing money like
crazy and if you put your money on a
bank account you are going to be lucky
if you get
two percent of interest rate there are
people on the defy space that are making
four percent
12 even 20 annually on their investments
so today
we are going to talk about defy or
decentralized
finance nicolas
and welcome to the video number six on
this series where i'm trying to explain
bitcoin encryption all this crazy
ecosystem
for beginners and developers as well if
you have been watching our videos before
thank you so much for your support and
for still being here with us
and if you like my explanations and you
like the way i teach and explain things
please consider leaving a like and
subscribing to the channel because your
support helps me
continue with this series because still
there is too much to explain
so let's get started with d5
defy is an umbrella term for many kinds
of applications but at their core
they are all financial applications and
they are decentralized that means there
is no
middleman there is no third party and
everything runs on smart contracts
the d5 world is exploding there are too
many new things coming up
all the time so i'm gonna give you some
examples of what you can do
right now with define for example we
have smart contract powered
banks we have applications right now
where you can go and
deposit money and you can lend it to
people and get interest rate or also
you can go and you can borrow money and
then of course you're going to have to
repay but all these
will be completely decentralized and
automatic without dealing with
any humans whatsoever we also have
decentralized exchanges where you can
trade your coins and you can buy
and sell without having to even reveal
your email for example you could even
buy
insurance against hackers and you can
even bet
on decentralized casinos now before we
keep going just make sure that all these
videos are for educational purposes
only you should do your own research and
you should use them at your own risk
this is only for educational purposes
only now before i can get started
showing you the biggest players of the
d5 ecosystem first we need to understand
one concept that is very very important
for the d5 world and that is
the concept of stable coins a stable
coin is
a cryptocurrency literally a
cryptocurrency you can send it
you can trade it you can put in your
wallet all that stuff but
it is packed or anchored to the us
dollar that means that the value of one
stable coin is equal to one u.s dollar
that's why they say
stable coin in the name it's stable it
doesn't go up and down like bitcoin does
it's stable one two one usually these
cryptocurrencies are backed by a company
so for example we have
usdt we have usdc we have also b usd in
the case of bus this is backed by
binance which is an exchange
so binance is promising that your one b
usd
equals to one u.s dollar that they have
on their bank account for example
now the cool thing about stable coins is
that of course first of all it's a
stable so if i buy stablecoin today
tomorrow is gonna be worth the same one
dollar one stablecoin
but also the fact that they are a
cryptocurrency means that i can do stuff
with them i can program things with them
we can use smart contracts with stable
coins
here is when we start building awesome
stuff one example of an
awesome d5 project is ave or eve i don't
know how to say it the point is
ave it is a liquidity pool what that
means is basically like a bank where you
can
borrow money or also you can go and lend
money to people
here for example is where as of today
you can deposit usdt or let's say busd
and you can make 9 to 12
per year just borrowing that money to
people now the coolest thing about all
these is that it's decentralized i can
just
lend my money to people and i can
receive interest rate on that money
without having to deal with any human
everything is programmed everything is
on the smart contract which is amazing
now thanks to smart contracts thanks to
this
awesomeness right now ave or eve has
nine billion dollars under management
there are nine
billion dollars of people depositing and
loaning from the other platform
and here there are no humans on the
process now let's move on from ave and
talk about
decentralized exchanges or taxes finance
coinbase bitcom all these are
centralized exchanges this means that if
i want to sell you
my bitcoin on binance binance is going
to take a commission a trading fee
also binance can close my account they
can limit my account they can do
whatever they want with my account
because it's a centralized exchange
now decentralized exchanges are the
complete opposite for example
uni swap or sushi swap or pancake swap
or so many of them out there
they are run by code they are not run by
people
in a decentralized exchange the users
are the ones that provide the liquidity
and for doing this
they receive some trading fees a pool is
how we can exchange
tokens without a middlemen for example
if i want to exchange
my wi-fi tokens for linked tokens i will
have to go to a wi-fi
link liquidity pool a liquidity pool is
basically like a smart contract that has
two symbols wi-fi and link and now what
i will do
is i will put some wi-fi tokens on that
contract and that contract will give me
some link tokens as you can see it's a
hundred percent automated process
so that's a liquidity pool again a smart
contract that has two
sets of tokens that it receives one and
you can spill the other
okay now the point is that users can be
the ones providing
the liquidity for the pool so let's say
for example that you have a thousand
dollars right and you want to invest
this thousand dollars what you can do is
let's say you buy
500 b usd or usdt some stablecoin and
then you buy 500 worth of ethereum now
you have
busd and ethereum you are going to put
your busd
and your ethereum into a usd ethereum
pool and if i for example i'm using a
decentralized exchange and i want to buy
ethereum and i have busd what i will do
is i will use
your pool and because i'm using your
pool you will get
some fees of the transaction because i'm
basically using the pool that you are
the liquidity provider of
remember the coolest thing about all
these is that that's all
in code code is low literally in all
this process there is no humans involved
this is all automatic you are going to
put your busd and your ethereum you're
going to start getting the fizz
automatically and
if i want to let's say buy ethereum with
my busd i'm gonna use your pool and i'm
gonna
just get my cons automatically nobody is
gonna interfere
on the trade there is no exchange
checking my email or my papers
nothing like that everything is running
on code literally and now
for our last example of applications in
this crazy d5 world there are websites
right now where using stable coins like
usdt
usdc all those things you can literally
bet on almost
anything that you want like anything
that's going on in the world you can bet
on that
for example just now i found two crazy
bits one is that you can bet if the
tokyo olympics are going to be cancelled
or not
and also you can bet who is going to
have more money by the end of
april is it going to be ill mosque or
jeff bezos you can literally
bet on that as you can see d5 is crazy
it's unstoppable and is only getting
started we are only seeing the beginning
of that
now before i go i just want to let you
know that i agree with you if you're
thinking that everything that i say
sounds too good to be true like i talked
about defy today we talked about nfts
before smart contracts shared computer
mining like all these things yeah they
sound too good to be true maybe you're
thinking like hey what is the catch like
there has to be something wrong with
this there has to be a problem with this
industry there is something that i'm not
telling you
and that's true i haven't been talking
about the problems of the bitcoin
industry
how for example mining bitcoin might be
bad for the environment and
all the things we have to consider like
all these things i haven't talked about
and that's what's gonna be
on the next video the next video is
going to be about the problems of the
crypto industries
so if you have any comments any
questions anything that you think that
maybe crypt is not so good at like what
about this what about that
all these things please leave them on
the comments because i'm going to be
looking at those comments and we're
going to talk about the
problems of this whole industry on the
next video i want to be the first one to
tell you
that it's not perfect everything is not
as good as it looks
there are some problems and we're going
to discuss it on the next video so make
sure you leave all your skepticism and
all your questions and all your things
on the comments okay thank you so much
for your support i wouldn't be able to
do this without you and without your
support
like i said that's it thank you leave a
like please subscribe
leave a comment and don't forget to be
happy don't forget to eat kimchi thumbs
up
see you on the next one problems of
crypto coming up next
bye